# **Thomas Beattie Haynsworth**

187A Rutledge Ave Charleston, SC 29403 Thomas.haynsworth@gmail.com Cell Phone: (908) 447-6537

## **Summary**

**Experienced management professional.** Successful in managing people and day to day operations demonstrated through strong leadership abilities, creative problem solving, and innovative and forward thinking. Effective accounting and general management experience exhibited by budget creation, purchasing and reconciliation skills.

## **Work Experience**

## **Wild Dunes Resort**

## **Boardwalk Inn & Village Housekeeping Manager**

January 2013 – Present

- Manage all aspects of the Housekeeping operation at Wild Dunes Resort: The Boardwalk Inn 93 room boutique hotel and The Village -150 unit condominium style hotel. The resort also includes 250 Homes/Condos throughout the gated community, a 10,000sqft conference center, 2 golf courses, 17 clay tennis courts and multiple dinning outlets.
- Oversee staff of 30 to 60 people between low and peak season.
- Responsible for all housekeeping operating expenses including payroll, inventories, guest supplies, capital projects and other departmental expenses.
- Realized a 10% departmental savings year over year through innovative staffing, scheduling and purchasing.
- Improved Housekeeper efficiency and employee satisfaction through training, coaching, and creative work distribution.
- Enhanced guest service satisfaction scores year over year through effective leadership, successful hiring, coaching, training and communication.

## Assistant Housekeeping Manager

March 2012 - January 2013

- Facilitated in budgeting, forecasting and re-forecasting.
- Conducted daily and monthly meetings to ensure full staff communications.
- Controlled daily/weekly/monthly purchasing, receiving, invoicing and billing.
- Created weekly schedules for Boardwalk Inn & Village departments.

#### **Guest Service Manager**

*January 2011 – March 2012* 

- Managed the Bell/Valet/Transportation operation for the entire resort with a staff of 15 to 30 employees.
- Implemented multiple standard operating procedures to improve guest/employee satisfaction.

#### Bell/Valet/Transportation Supervisor

December 2009 – January 2011

- Supervised two valet operations and transportation for entire resort through efficient scheduling and hands on management
- Collaborated with Front Desk operation to assure communication between teams.

## **Front Desk Agent**

September 2008 – December 2009

• Maintained control of high volume front office operations while providing high level of service.

### Education

**Champlain College,** Burlington VT *BS in Hotel & Restaurant Management* 

August 2004 - May 2008

Bond University, Queensland Australia

January 2007 - May 2007

# Special Training/Skills/Accolades

- Wild Dunes Resort "Leader of the Quarter" Q1 2014
- Wild Dunes Resort "Associate of the Year" 2010
- Toastmasters public speaking member
- Accumulated approximately 40 hours of training annually (Leadership skills, progressive discipline, best hiring practices, coaching/counseling, professional cleaning training, sharps/chemical safety training)
- Proficient in Microsoft Office applications including Word, Excel, PowerPoint.